# BEN HICKSON SOFTWARE

- **■** bzhickson@gmail.com
- line benhickson.com

**ENGINEER** 

- **4**23-715-6852
- ♥ Brooklyn, NY
- **in** benhickson
- n benhickson

Full-stack engineer experienced with React, Angular, and Rails, and fluent in JavaScript, PHP, and Ruby. Excellent at independent and collaborative work with distributed teams.

Background in the media industry, focused on technical mastery, project management, and client relations, with a track record of delivering work ontime, to-spec, and in-budget. Interested in leveraging technology in projects that can benefit society in profound ways.

### Skills

### **FRAMEWORKS**

Angular

React

Ruby on Rails

Flask

Express

Wordpress

#### **LANGUAGES**

**JavaScript** 

PHP

TypeScript

Ruby

Python SQL

SKILLS

### Application Architecture and

Open-source (OSS)

Cloud Deployment

Project Planning and Management

### **MEDIA**

File Compression and Delivery Optimization

Video Editing

2D Animation

Color Grading

Sound Mixing

# Experience

### Our Hometown Software Engineer

Remote | Brooklyn, NY August 2020 - Current

- Developed a system to orchestrate the error logs and performance analytics of a network of 200+ production websites into a centralized dashboard.
- Work with engineering team to handle client requests, collaborating via a ticket system.
- Currently: Developing a new theme framework to deploy across the network of sites.

### Lonelyleap Film Technical Manager

Brooklyn, NY 2013 - 2020

- Managed the post-production department (resources and staff), supervised output, and optimized storage processes.
- Worked directly with clients and led production teams on many projects, with budgets ranging from \$50k \$300k, for a wide variety of clients, including Google, Nokia, and Uber.
- Developed a web app to enable globally-distributed teams to upload video assets to a centralized server, implemented a video transcode queue, and built tagging and search functionality. Integrated it into our project workflow, and deployed it to our team.
- Developed a web app to manage credit card transactions, which enabled all cardholders to categorize expenses by project and expense type, organizing the data for project managers, and exporting files which can be imported into quickbooks automatically. Integrated an automated polling system for the bank's OFX API endpoints to get new transactions daily, and integrated with the Cloudinary API to allow users to upload receipt images.

# **Projects**

### Go Room

App Backend (Rails) | Poker Backend (NodeJS) | Frontend (Angular) | Portfolio Page | Live Site

Browser-based group video chat app (nothing to install!), with extensibility at its core. Perfect for social distancing!

- Implemented as an Angular (version 9) application, with components built for efficient memory management.
- Implemented main backend as a Rails API with a MySQL database, handling authentication with JWT.
  Built a complete multiplayer poker application, leveraging websockets (socket.io), on a NodeJS / Express backend.
- Multi-backend authentication is handled using federated JWTs.
- Implemented a paradigm of authenticated anonymous users, to increase conversions.

#### The Bad Idea Machine

Backend (Rails) | Frontend (React) | Portfolio Page | Live Site

Idea Generation Application for Advertising Creatives

- Trained a GPT-2-based neural network to generate ideas in the form of a short "pitch".
- React frontend, Rails backend, JWT Authentication
- Deployed with Netlify and Heroku

### **Traversalist**

### GitHub | Portfolio Page | Live Site

A website featuring articles across different themes, at the intersection of science, philosophy, and society.

- Implemented custom routing functionality, optimizing requests for speed.
- Developed a custom image generation and caching engine with the PHP Imagick module, to optimize images.
- Developed a consistent, easy-to-use API for interacting with the image engine and requesting resources.

### Stock Archive

#### GitHub | Portfolio Page

Content management system for video teams, surfacing unused footage with team members around the world.

- Envisioned, created, and deployed the application in my company, building it into our processes.
- Implemented automation queues to transcode uploaded assets into multiple resolutions and thumbnails.
- Implemented a custom media server to access transcoded assets with a consistent API.
- Built custom tagging and search engine functionality.
- Ensured full security for uploaded assets, and all access is logged for regulatory compliance.
- Integrated Clarifai's Al-powered image recognition technology.

### Education

Flatiron School

Full Stack Web Development Immersive, Ruby on Rails and React

Middle Tennessee State University BBA, Finance

2007 - 2011

2020 - 2020